hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft and
you might be wondering why I'm walking
backwards and that's because behind me I
have sussed out how to do the back of
this building I've been doing some
off-camera building for Sahara and this
particular part has been through about
three different designs before I finally
settled on this one the trickiest part
was getting this bit here to look right
and there's actually a fresh room in
here that I plan to use a little bit
later on in the episode there's
absolutely nothing going on or no
differences inside the main Warehouse
building at the moment because the
Redstone is still under construction and
I don't want to go ahead and build
anything important there because the
Redstone does come first this building
however I can do a little bit more
because as you can see I have emptied
out some of this area and I have filled
it up with some blank walls the
interface for Sahara is going to go
somewhere around here the pr I believe
that the the actual interface is only
going to be like two blocks so that
might actually look a little bit strange
in the context of this great big wall
but as you can see I've been doing some
work now this is going to be the
architect or the Sahara nether portal so
let's get this set up shall we so if I
pop through it's probably going to put
me at somebody else's portal that's the
one in the shopping district if we
follow the minimap Because the actual
nether Hub is one giant map of the
entire Island it actually makes it
pretty easy to put our portal and that
would be right about here so in theory
if I place the portal like so this
should link it up
perfect absolutely perfect so if you
want to go to Sahara through the nether
it's super super easy now but as for the
building of Sahara there's still a lot
to do like it may seem like we've got a
lot of it done and we have we have got a
lot done
but it's such a massive project it's
hard to keep the steam going at a
hundred percent in order to get this
done for example this roof alone you can
see how much quartz is needed to finish
this and I used all of my Supply just
getting this outer ring done so what I
did was I spent about an hour and a half
Gathering all of this nether quartz ore
and I thought I'd spend the start of
this episode at least just time lapsing
getting this part done so let's let's
grind this out
so I've never actually done this before
where you make a time lapse where you
take all the aura of something you place
it all down and then you literally
remove it all as one big time lapse
yeah and I must admit it took me a
really long time so I don't think I'll
be doing it again but it was necessary
to get all of this quartz and my
goodness was there a lot in the end but
eventually it got the job done or
well
did it I can't believe it after that
time lapse you saw me placing all that
quartz or getting rid of it and then
starting placing it all the way around
and look 12 blocks of quartz slab left
I can't I haven't got enough I've got
nothing I've just got nothing to fill
this up with I'm gonna have to go and
get some more quartz I thought huh this
is gonna be enough and I'll have some
left over no this is one of the most
expensive blocks in the game I I
literally I cannot believe that it
wasn't enough but as I was building this
I was sort of doing my quartz or and
stuff and as I was going I kind of
stopped for a second and I looked over
there and I I was like what so now I'm
I'm in the middle of time lapsing and I
want to go and check this out I haven't
been yet because I wanted to record that
little time lapse there but there's
something that that is a that is a
hideous hideous mask and it's on my
pickle shop so let's go and have a look
what's going on over here oh it's it's a
salmon head oh it's a salmon oh okay
from this angle I couldn't tell what it
was from here
it just it's got a really like
kind of kind of face but when you get
around the corner when you actually face
it on you can see yeah that's 100
a salmon mask it's not even like a
salmon head or a salmon face it's it's
literally got a bit around it so let's
go and oh my goodness I mean this is one
of my favorite things that's going on in
the server
slowly very slowly this little parrot
has been
it just you know doing his business and
it's creeping it's creeping everywhere
it's spreading it's it's almost it's oh
it's getting in Cherry this is this is
gross and it's oh it's drifted down into
the pickle shop this is absolutely lewd
this is season six worth of bird poop
and since we're here we should actually
go and have a look in the pickle shop
maybe that's maybe that's why they've
done it the salmon wants me to go and
check inside the pickle shop
well if the salmon was here there's no
way for me to tell because there's
pickles absolutely everywhere I forgot
about all the pickle puns this water can
be a little bit cumbersome
buy more pickles it's a pretty sweet
deal
oh nice we've actually sold some
we've actually sold a lot wait there's I
think there's one up here as well
no nothing in that one
oh we've sold all of our pickles I mean
pickles aren't let's be honest a very
big seller not many people need them but
13 diamonds not that bad I don't know
who needs that many pickles unless the
Salmon's actually bought all of my
pickles and that's their wave because
you know here's the thing I haven't
checked my pickle shop in I don't know
weeks and weeks and weeks maybe it must
have been like episode 20 where I last
checked it because literally no one was
buying pickles maybe the salmon is
behind it well at least they paid for it
at least they've paid for the pickles if
anyone knows who did buy them please let
me know but if not maybe it was the
salmon that's really interesting you
know what I think I'm gonna leave that
there I I mean that was a prank in the
first place that was a Harry Potter
pickle and now it's a salmon man Harry
Potter Biggle so I guess what I need to
do is I'm gonna have to go and gather
just a little bit more quartz to fix
this up I believe right now Mumbo is
actually doing some Redstone it's about
time Mumbo look at that there's loads of
progress and there's already there's
already mobs in there already mob
spawning Light It Up Mumbo anyway let's
go and grab this quartz so that we can
kind of try and get this finished
I I don't know what's going on but I
can't fly it literally won't let me look
watch this it's like my Rockets just
don't go anywhere
even if I take it off
and I put it back on
it just it's just consuming the
fireworks what is this look is this
smells a bit I think I'm gonna have to
just re-log there we go now we're flying
and it's actually been quite a long time
since we got this far and I've been
doing lots and lots of work to it so I
went and got myself some more quartz and
we're actually going to finish this off
right now this is a really good feeling
and done but that's not all that I've
been working on I've actually been
working really hard on the whole of the
Sahara build and trying to get it as
done as possible so I've added in these
two trees it's kind of cut off because
of the building and yeah regrettably I
would actually have put four in there
but there's no way I'm taking them down
and making for another one see like the
spacing is probably a bit too much I
probably should have had one two three
then four which is annoying in fact I
probably could just shift over that one
and then make another there which
wouldn't be as much work but either way
the inside is what I've been working on
the most and I've actually spent a
really decent amount of time trying to
make this a really cool interior so at
the moment I'm thinking this is where
the console is going to be this is where
you actually make your order for Sahara
now I've tried my best to actually mob
proof it you can see I've put carpet
everywhere I've even added some nice
detailing on the roof there's like end
rods that are act as light and it's like
it's hanging from there I've really put
in a lot of effort to try and make this
Lobby look really attractive to anyone
that comes into the shop I've also added
a couple of elevators here just some
bubble elevators with some arrows
pointing the direction that they go in
but up here I've still got a lot to do
so yeah I basically went to get Quartz
and I came back and worked on all this
and boy oh boy did I use quite a lot of
materials
now over here you'll notice that I've
been making these big holes and what
I've been thinking is that I can do the
glass fog trick to try and make
something more decorative and then I'm
thinking in here we have a couple of
layers of water and it's kind of like
having a fountain without removing all
the sand in the middle and I think that
would look really nice but I'm not
actually sure how deep I need to go to
make this fog effect work really well
can
excuse he's just walked into me oh he's
seen he's seeing me now
[Laughter]
well there's a there's a full-on walk
yep there's a full-on war going on here
there's something weird about this area
Okay because seriously like the the
entire mob cap can spawn in this one
tiny cave and it's actually really bad
this is probably a good idea to get this
whole thing lit up overall I think in a
few days time maybe a week I can have
all of the building done I've really
enjoyed this project so far but I've
actually started doing something with
this room here and this is part of my
marketing campaign so this is a really
big part of Sahara so I've got to make
sure that I get this right first time
what we're going to be producing here
is some Sahara news or should we call it
hermit news presented by Sahara so I'm I
am going to take uh scars design for the
camera because we're gonna need a camera
for this and he made a really cool
design so I I'm gonna I'm gonna use that
so I've made a slightly different
version to the one that scar made over
at the Vex tank but we've got ourselves
a camera which uh there's such a cool
design what we need now is just a little
bit of Studio lighting so that we can
film our very first hermit news
so brought to you by Sahara
this is hermit news I think that I'm
ready to make this this could be really
really cool so yes this is this is like
sponsored news I guess like this is a
Sahara back so of course we're going to
be pushing an agenda in our news stories
but this could be a really really fun
thing I've already got a few like little
little things in mind so maybe what we
should do is I'm just gonna go ahead and
make it and see and see what happens
oh boy here we go all right let's start
filming shall we
[Music]
good evening and welcome to hermit news
tonight's top stories Ariana Grande's
new album I'm agreeing with you tops the
chance for 12 weeks in a row an ugly
mask that looks like a salmon has
appeared on the pickle shop and in a
mysterious turn of events all the
pickles have sold out and Mumbo slime
shop is still not stocked and now for
our top story a major waste spill has
been discovered at a Concor retailer in
the shopping district let's go over to
grian who is out in the field
thank you Grand as you can see behind me
we're looking at one of the worst
environmental disasters of season six it
would appear that their waste disposal
pipes have been clogged for months but
time finally has taken its toll and it
is now spewing out waste into the
surrounding environment this throws into
question the care of Duty concorp has
shown the shopping district and we are
yet to hear a response from them we can
only hope that other companies will be
more considerate and clean with their
building
back to you Korean and green
thank you Green in other unrelated news
Sahara has been progressing greatly in
the last few weeks having completed the
majority of their building
they have even started building an
offshore Wind Farm to power their
business venture talk about sustainable
Enterprise and that's it from us and
hermit news
good evening and hashtag shop at Sahara
and that's a wrap on the first hermit
news
I think that went pretty well don't you
so I was thinking basically what we
could do is Sahara news every now and
again to update people on the ongoings
of the server obviously Sahara are going
for some more sustainable energy than
the toxic sludge that is going on with
Concord this is a brilliant look at that
oh it's even it's even grown since the
last time since the report since the
report happened it's gotten even bigger
oh I totally forgot wait I didn't
realize you could just bounce off it
when you were flying I thought it
damaged you even when you were when you
were flying I thought it didn't matter I
thought fall damage was full damage
apparently not so what happens if you
fall from a really do you get like a
really big bounce
I didn't even hit the slime
oh that's so embarrassing
I still want to see if you bounce off it
though if I I do I boast about how good
I am at flying and then I do this I
think I need to give up my title as the
best flyer on the server
okay let's try this again and this time
I'm going to hit the Slime properly
all right here we go
ah
oh nice you could get some real air on
that that's so cool I was pretty sure I
was gonna die but I actually just died
from Bad flying so what I'm thinking we
can do is we can definitely build on
this whole news thing going on so there
are plenty of concorp shops in the
shopping district and basically the plan
is to give them a really bad reputation
I mean they already have a bad
reputation but like look at this this
one is like a it's an engine it's
chucking out loads of like look at this
they have zero environmental concern
look at all the junk that's coming out
of this honestly they're even affecting
the weather affecting the weather it's
unbelievable so the news are going to
report on that and report on the good
things that Sahara are doing but that is
only part of my advertising campaigns
honestly I have a lot of ideas this is
just about giving Sahara a bit of a good
reputation before we've even gotten
started over the next few episodes I
plan on doing some really intense
marketing schemes to try and get all of
the Hermits to start shopping at Sahara
but unfortunately as much as I want to
start advertising properly there's
really not much chance of me advertising
effectively if we don't even have a
product we don't have the full shop yet
it's just it's just not finished so
we've really really got to get a move on
with all of the building and the
Redstone as fun as it is we just need to
actually start selling something because
I can't advertise a shop that isn't even
open yet and then we've got to have a
grand opening day it's it's there's a
lot of work to do here
so going back into the building and
speaking of all the work that we've got
to do I should at least try and get this
Courtyard finished I'm really not sure
if I like this giant Square thing it
doesn't look particularly good at the
moment especially as this is four blocks
that's three but either way I wanted to
try out this glass trick and I'm I'm
honestly not sure how many layers you
need to do in order to make this work
but I'm pretty sure I know the theory
and I've got a shulker box full of the
glass right here but it's probably wise
to start from the bottom for those of
you that don't really know this trick
all you have to do is do a layer of
glass of stained glass for that matter
and you have to have a space of air then
another layer then another and you
repeat multiple layers and then when you
look down they all kind of like fade
into one it gives this really cool
effect there we go so it you kind of get
the idea obviously I definitely have not
done enough layers you've got to do
really quite a lot of these to get the
full effect but you can see where it's
going and probably I've I've maybe done
the wrongs colored glass I could have
done something else I may even just blow
this whole thing up with TNT and start
over again because yeah I'm not I'm not
sure if this is the right direction I
like the idea of having water all along
here as it's like it's like resemblance
of a of a fountain but this glass thing
this was just an experiment
one thing that I was pretty certain that
I wanted to do was maybe add some
bookshelves like some decorative
bookshelves for this main part because
well I I do actually need some
decoration in here that isn't just super
ultra modern so maybe some tall
bookshelves might might make us seem a
bit more sophisticated than we perhaps
are here at Sahara I actually bought all
of these with emeralds but I'm thinking
I'm probably gonna need a lot more
something like that with the shelving
could look really cool
I don't really know if it fits it
definitely matches the floor I'm gonna
have to do a lot of experimenting I did
a lot of experimenting with just the
shape of this room I think this design
up here went through three or four
iterations before we got anywhere near
where it is so this might take a few
attempts as well but I kind of wanted to
show you what what I do because a lot of
the time I build this off camera and
then I just show you the finished thing
but this time I wanted to show you how
many times I mess up before I get the
right design
well anyway you need to let me know in
the comments whether I should continue
with the news thing see if that works it
was a lot of fun to make but it is a lot
of effort so if it's not a good idea
then I'll ditch it but I I had a lot of
fun with it I think it could be really
funny show concorp who's boss that's the
goal of this show concorp who rules the
hermitcraft server and we're the new guy
on the Block and we're gonna sell
everything and I've got to admit if you
take a good look around you fly up in
the sky
and you take a look at the shopping
district as a whole
Sahara really is one of the most obvious
things maybe not from Miss angle because
we got our big ball in the way but round
like this you can see how enormous
Sahara is and I'm really intrigued to
get this on a separate server and get
like a world edit count of how many
blocks we used I think that'd be a
really interesting statistic well anyway
we have done an awful lot of work today
why scar following me Scott what are you
doing that's my job scar what are you
doing no no okay so that's what that
feels like I thought I was lacking
anyway that's it from me everyone thank
you very much for watching I am having a
great time working on Sahara and I can't
wait to get into the marketing much more
fully obviously my job is starting to
come to an end when it comes to the
building once this is done actually you
know what from the air that doesn't look
bad at all but my job on the whole is
starting to come to an end the Redstone
might be a long ways off I mean I don't
even know what's going on there but you
can see that my building here oh that
wasn't me but the building here it's and
you know all the details and stuff it's
all starting to get finished and when
the building's done there might still
need to be Redstone but it'll be my job
to start advertising this as much as
possible
but anyway thank you very much for
watching everyone I hope you've enjoyed
this episode and you know what
for the first time ever and I I do mean
this first time ever
if you enjoy the hermitcraft series and
we're like 59 episodes in would you
consider subscribing to my channel I've
never ever ever
asked anyone to subscribe to my channel
like this before and it feels really
really weird but you'd be surprised how
many people that watch this series
aren't actually subscribed to my channel
and I want to know if this message
actually does any different so if I see
a big increase in subscribers I'll know
that you saw it anyway thank you very
much for watching everyone and I'll see
you in the next episode goodbye